# **YIQUAN WANG**

yiquan2@illinois.edu | Website: www.yiquan2.com

# **Professional Summary**

Passionate about the integration of biological and computational sciences, with 6+ years of collaborative research experience in deep learning applications and next-generation sequencing analysis. Interdisciplinary research experience in diverse fields (Immunology, Virology, Structural Biology and Computational Biology).

## **Education**

**2020 - Present University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign**, Champaign, IL *Biochemistry*, *Doctor of Philosophy* 

**2015 - 2019**Chongqing University, Chongqing, China
Bioenqineering, Bachelor of Bioenqineering

# **Professional Experience**

2020 - Present	University Of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL Biochemistry (Carter Fellow), Doctor of Philosophy Viral evolution, Antibody Engineering, Deep Learning, Model Explainability
2022 - 2023	<b>Genentech Inc,</b> San Francisco, CA Structural and Computational Biology, Intern Graph Neural Networks; Protein Function; Antibody Design
2019 - 2020	The University of Hong Kong - Pasteur Research Pole, HK School of public health, Research Assistant Viral evolution, Immune Responses, DNA/RNA seq
2018 - 2019	Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Visiting student Mouse Models; In Vitro Translation System
2017 - 2018	Chongqing University, Chongqing Bioengineering, Undergraduate Researcher Fluorescent Nanoparticles: Hierarchical Encapsulation Method

## **Publications**

\*Equal contribution.

### **Preprints**

Teo QW\*, <u>Wang Y\*</u>, Lv H\*, Tan TJC, Mao KJ, Wu NC. Deep mutational scanning of influenza A virus NEP reveals pleiotropic mutations in its N-terminal domain. bioRxiv (2024): 2024-05.

Yang K, Liu J, Wu J, Yang C, Fung YR, Li S, Huang Z, Cao X, Wang X, <u>Wang Y</u>, Ji H. If llm is the wizard, then code is the wand: A survey on how code empowers large language models to serve as intelligent agents. arXiv preprint arXiv:2401.00812. 2024 Jan 1.

Lamers MM\*, Breugem TI\*, Mykytyn AZ\*, **Wang Y**, Groen N, Knoops K, Schipper D, van der Vaart J, Koopman CD, Zhang J, Wu DC, van den Doel PB, Bestebroer T, GeurtsvanKessel CH, Peters PJ, Muraro MJ, Clevers H, Wu NC, Haagmans BL. Human organoid systems reveal in vitro correlates of fitness for SARS-CoV-2 B.1.1.7. *bioRxiv* DOI: 10.1101/2021.05.03.441080

#### 2024

**Wang Y\***, Lv H\*, Lei R, Yeung YH, Shen IR, Choi D, Teo QW, Tan TJ, Gopal AB, Chen X, Graham CS. An explainable language model for antibody specificity prediction using curated influenza hemagglutinin antibodies. *Immunity* (*In press*).

## 2023

Wong LY, Odle A, Luhmann E, Wu DC, <u>Wang Y</u>, Teo QW, Ptak C, Sariol A, Lowery S, Mack M, Meyerholz DK. Contrasting roles of MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 internal proteins in pathogenesis in mice. *Mbio*. 2023 Dec 19:14(6):e02476-23.

Teo QW\*, Wang Y\*, Lv H\*, Tan TJ, Lei R, Mao KJ, Wu NC. Stringent and complex sequence constraints of an IGHV1-69 broadly neutralizing antibody to influenza HA stem. *Cell reports*. 2023 Nov 28;42(11).

Lei R, Kim W, Lv H, Mou Z, Scherm MJ, Schmitz AJ, Turner JS, Tan TJ, <u>Wang Y</u>, Ouyang WO, Liang W. Leveraging vaccination-induced protective antibodies to define conserved epitopes on influenza N2 neuraminidase. *Immunity*. 2023 Nov 14;56(11):2621-34.

Lei R, Garcia AH, Tan TJ, Teo QW, <u>Wang Y</u>, Zhang X, Luo S, Nair SK, Peng J, Wu NC. Mutational fitness landscape of human influenza H<sub>3</sub>N<sub>2</sub> neuraminidase. *Cell reports*. Jan <sub>31;42</sub>(1). (2023)

#### 2022

Yuan M, <u>Wang Y</u>, Lv H, Tan TJC, Wilson IA, Wu NC. Molecular analysis of a public cross-neutralizing antibody response to SARS-CoV-2. *Cell Reports* 41:111650 (2022)

Lei R, Tan TJC, Hernandez Garcia A, <u>Wang Y</u>, Diefenbacher M, Teo C, Gopan G, Tavakoli Dargani Z, Teo QW, Graham CS, Brooke CB, Nair SK, Wu NC. Prevalence and mechanisms of evolutionary contingency in human influenza H<sub>3</sub>N<sub>2</sub> neuraminidase. *Nature Communications* 13:6443 (2022)

Liu T, Wang Y, Tan TJC, Wu NC#, Brooke CB#. The evolutionary potential of influenza A virus hemagglutinin is highly constrained by epistatic interactions with neuraminidase. *Cell Host & Microbe* 30:1363-1369.e4 (2022)

Liang W, Tan TJC, <u>Wang Y</u>, Lv H, Sun Y, Bruzzone R, Mok CKP\*, Wu NC\*. Egg-adaptive mutations of human influenza H<sub>3</sub>N<sub>2</sub> virus are contingent on natural evolution. *PLoS Pathogens* 18:e1010875 (2022)

<u>Wang Y</u>\*, Yuan M\*, Lv H, Peng J, Wilson IA, Wu NC. A large-scale systematic survey reveals recurring molecular features of public antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2. *Immunity* 55(6):1105-1117 (2022). (Cover)

#### 2021

**Wang Y\***, Lei R\*, Nourmohammad A, Wu NC. Antigenic evolution of human influenza H<sub>3</sub>N<sub>2</sub> neuraminidase is constrained by charge balancing. *eLife* 10:e72516 (2021)

Lv H\*, Tsang OTY\*, So RTY, <u>Wang Y</u>, Yuan M, Liu H, Yip GK, Teo QW, Yihan Lin Y, Liang W, Wang J, Ng WW, Wilson IA, Peiris JSM, Wu NC#, Mok CKP#. Homologous and heterologous serological response to the N-terminal domain of SARS-CoV-2 in humans and mice. *European Journal of Immunology* 51:2296-2305 (2021)

Tan TJC\*, Yuan M\*, Kuzelka K, Padron GC, Beal JR, Chen X, <u>Wang Y</u>, Rivera-Cardona J, Zhu X, Stadtmueller BM, Brooke CB, Wilson IA\*, Wu NC\*. Sequence signatures of two public antibody clonotypes that bind SARS-CoV-2 receptor binding domain. *Nature Communications* 12:3815 (2021)

Lamers MM, Mykytyn AZ, Breugem TI, **Wang Y**, Wu DC, Riesebosch S, van den Doel PB, Schipper D, Bestebroer T, Wu NC, Haagmans BL. Human airway cells prevent SARS-CoV-2 multibasic cleavage site cell culture adaptation. *eLife* 10:e66815 (2021)

#### 2020

Lv H\*, Wu NC\*, Tsang OTY\*, Yuan M, Perera RAPM, Leung WS, So RTY, Chan JMC, Yip GK, Chik TSH, **Wang Y**, Choi CYC, Lin Y, Ng WW, Zhao J, Poon LLM, Peiris JSM\*, Wilson IA\*, Mok CKP\*. Cross-reactive antibody response between SARS-CoV-2 and SARS-CoV infections. *Cell Reports* 31:107725 (2020)

## 2018

**Wang, Y\***, Wei Zhou\*, Feng Chen, Kaiyao Sun, Jixi Zhang, Ezgi Özliselib, and Jessica M. Rosenholm. "Terbium complexes encapsulated in hierarchically organized hybrid MOF particles toward stable luminescence in aqueous media." *CrystEngComm* 20.30 (2018): 4225-4229.

## Talks & Presentations

2024-06	American Society for Virology  Talk: An Explainable Language Model for Antibody Specificity Prediction
2024-02	<b>Biophysical Society</b> Poster: An Explainable Language Model for Antibody Specificity Prediction
2022-06	<b>Keystone symposia</b> Poster: A large-scale systematic survey reveals recurring molecular features of public antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2
2022-07	American Society for Virology Annual Meeting Talk: Antigenic evolution of human influenza H3N2 neuraminidase is constrained by charge balancing

# Awards & Fellowships

- Art of Science Image Contest Winner (2024)
- Biophysical Society Travel Award (2024)
- "Life Inspiring" Art Competition Second Place Winner (2023)
- HERBERT E. CARTER FELLOWSHIP (2023)
- Biochemistry Department Graduate Student Conference (Travel) Awards (2022)
- Chongqing University Excellent Student Comprehensive Scholarship (2015 2019)
- National Encouragement Scholarship (2015 2019)
- "Meritorious Winner" in The Mathematical Contest in Modeling, COMAP (2017)